# **Tom L Jenkins**

**PhD** 

**Curriculum Vitae** 

Exeter, United Kingdom

+44 7880 950409

▼ Tom.L.Jenkins@outloogergrgk.com

tomjenkins.netlify.app

Tom-Jenkins

#### **Profile**

An experienced scientist and research professional with a demonstrated history of working on highly diverse projects in both academic and public sector organisations. My areas of expertise include bioinformatics, geospatial analysis, data science and software development. Previous projects include population genomics and whole genome sequencing, predicting habitat suitability using machine learning, and developing software applications for internal and external customers.

## **Employment**

Apr 2022-Present Bioinformatician & Software Developer Animal and Plant Health Agency

Feb 2021-Mar 2022 Senior Data Analyst Natural England
Dec 2018-Jan 2021 Postdoctoral Research Associate University of Exeter

### **Qualifications**

2018	PhD	Evolutionary Biology	University of Exeter
2014	MRes	Biodiversity, Informatics and Genomics	Imperial Colleage London
2010	BSc	Marine Biology	Swansea University

## **Computer Skills**

Skill Bioinformatics, Data wrangling, DataViz, Geocomputation, Modelling, Web development Tools R, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Linux, Nextflow, GitHub, AWS, R Shiny, VS Code

#### **Selected Communication and Awards**

2022	Interview	Live interview on BBC Radio Wales Drive to discuss published research on coral	
		habitat suitability modelling	
2021	Interview	Pre-recorded interview on BBC Radio Cornwall to discuss published research on	
		red algae population genomics	
2019	Award	British Ecological Society Research Grant (£5,000)	
2018	Talk	Invited talk at Aquaculture Research Collaborative Hub UK Annual Conference	
2018	Award	Heredity Fieldwork Grant (£1,284)	

#### **Selected Publications**

- ➤ Jenkins TL, Stevens JR (2022). Predicting habitat suitability and range shifts under projected climate change for two octocorals in the north-east Atlantic. PeerJ 10, e13509.
- ➤ Jenkins TL, Guillemin M-L, Simon-Nutbrown C, Burdett HL, Stevens JR, Peña V (2021). Whole genome genotyping reveals discrete genetic diversity in north-east Atlantic maerl beds. Evolutionary Applications 14, 1558–1571.
- ➤ Houston RD, Bean TP, Macqueen DJ, Gundappa MK, Jin YH, **Jenkins TL**, *et al.* (2020). Harnessing genomics to fast-track genetic improvement in aquaculture. Nature Reviews Genetics 21, 389–409.